[   {
        "id": "1",
        "question" : "In Nepal, what is the minimum age requirement for obtaining a motorcycle license?",
        "options": [
            "16 years",
            "18 years",
            "20 years",
            "22 years"
        ],
        "answer": "16 years"
    },
    {
        "id": "2",
        "question" : "When riding a motorcycle, what is the most important safety gear to wear?",
        "options": [
            "Gloves",
            "Jacket",
            "Helmet",
            "Boots"
        ],
        "answer": "Helmet"
    },
    {
        "id": "3",
        "question" : "What should you do at a 'Stop' sign?",
        "options": [
            "Slow down and proceed with caution",
            "Come to a complete stop and proceed when it's safe",
            "Ignore the sign if the road is clear",
            "Honk and proceed"
        ],
        "answer": "Come to a complete stop and proceed when it's safe"
    },
    {
        "id": "4",
        "question" : "What does a red traffic light indicate?",
        "options": [
            "Go",
            "Proceed with caution",
            "Stop",
            "Slow down"
        ],
        "answer": "Stop"
    },
    {
        "id": "5",
        "question" : "When carrying a passenger on your motorcycle, where should they sit?",
        "options": [
            "In front of the rider",
            "On the rear seat behind the rider",
            "On the handlebars",
            "Anywhere on the motorcycle"
        ],
        "answer": "On the rear seat behind the rider"
    },
    {
        "id": "6",
        "question" : "What should you do if you encounter a pothole on the road?",
        "options": [
            "Accelerate to go over it quickly",
            "Swerve to avoid it",
            "Brake hard",
            "Gradually reduce speed and ride straight over it"
        ],
        "answer": "Gradually reduce speed and ride straight over it"
    },
    {
        "id": "7",
        "question" : "When riding a motorcycle, what should you do to make yourself more visible to other road users?",
        "options": [
            "Ride in the blind spots of other vehicles",
            "Use the motorcycle's horn frequently",
            "Wear brightly colored clothing and use reflective materials",
            "Ride close to the center line of the road"
        ],
        "answer": "Wear brightly colored clothing and use reflective materials"
    },
    {
        "id": "8",
        "question" : "What is the legal blood alcohol concentration (BAC) limit for motorcycle riders in Nepal?",
        "options": [
            "0.02%",
            "0.04%",
            "0.06%",
            "0.08%"
        ],
        "answer": "0.02%"
    },
    {
        "id": "9",
        "question" : "When riding a motorcycle, what should you do if it starts to rain?",
        "options": [
            "Increase speed to get to your destination faster",
            "Continue at the same speed",
            "Pull over and wait for the rain to stop",
            "Reduce speed and increase following distance"
        ],
        "answer": "Reduce speed and increase following distance"
    },
    {
        "id": "10",
        "question" : "What is the first thing you should check before starting a motorcycle?",
        "options": [
            "Brakes",
            "Lights and indicators",
            "Oil level",
            "Tire pressure"
        ],
        "answer": "Lights and indicators"
    },
    {
            "id": "11",
            "question" : "What should you do if you experience a tire blowout while riding?",
            "options": [
                "Brake hard to stop quickly",
                "Grip the handlebars firmly and ease off the throttle",
                "Accelerate to maintain control",
                "Swerve to the side of the road"
            ],
            "answer": "Grip the handlebars firmly and ease off the throttle"
        },
        {
            "id": "12",
            "question" : "When should you use your motorcycle's horn?",
            "options": [
                "To greet other riders",
                "To alert others of your presence in a non-emergency situation",
                "To express frustration with other road users",
                "To indicate your intention to overtake"
            ],
            "answer": "To alert others of your presence in a non-emergency situation"
        },
        {
            "id": "13",
            "question" : "What is the primary purpose of wearing proper riding gear?",
            "options": [
                "To look stylish",
                "To stay cool in hot weather",
                "To reduce wind resistance",
                "To protect yourself in case of a fall or accident"
            ],
            "answer": "To protect yourself in case of a fall or accident"
        },
        {
            "id": "14",
            "question" : "What should you do before changing lanes or making a turn?",
            "options": [
                "Signal your intention and check your mirrors",
                "Speed up to merge quickly",
                "Assume others will give you space",
                "Check your phone for messages"
            ],
            "answer": "Signal your intention and check your mirrors"
        },
        {
            "id": "15",
            "question" : "What is the correct riding position for maximum control and stability?",
            "options": [
                "Leaning as far as possible into turns",
                "Upright position with a relaxed grip on the handlebars",
                "Leaning back while turning",
                "Extending your legs outward while turning"
            ],
            "answer": "Upright position with a relaxed grip on the handlebars"
        },
        {
            "id": "16",
            "question" : "What is the recommended minimum following distance when riding a motorcycle?",
            "options": [
                "1 second",
                "2 seconds",
                "3 seconds",
                "4 seconds"
            ],
            "answer": "2 seconds"
        },
        {
            "id": "17",
            "question" : "What is the maximum allowable blood alcohol concentration (BAC) for a motorcycle rider under 21 years of age in Nepal?",
            "options": [
                "0.00%",
                "0.02%",
                "0.04%",
                "0.06%"
            ],
            "answer": "0.00%"
        },
        {
            "id": "18",
            "question" : "What does it mean if you see a hand signal from a vehicle ahead of you?",
            "options": [
                "They are waving hello",
                "They are indicating a turn or stop",
                "They are indicating a lane change",
                "They are asking for directions"
            ],
            "answer": "They are indicating a turn or stop"
        },
        {
            "id": "19",
            "question" : "When should you use both brakes on your motorcycle for maximum stopping power?",
            "options": [
                "Only in emergencies",
                "Only at high speeds",
                "In normal braking situations",
                "Never use both brakes at the same time"
            ],
            "answer": "In normal braking situations"
        },
        {
            "id": "20",
            "question" : "What should you do if you are being tailgated by another vehicle?",
            "options": [
                "Speed up to create more space",
                "Brake suddenly to warn the driver",
                "Change lanes and let them pass",
                "Ignore them and continue at your current speed"
            ],
            "answer": "Change lanes and let them pass"
        },
        {
            "id": "21",
            "question" : "When riding a motorcycle, what should you do to increase your visibility to other road users?",
            "options": [
                "Use high beam headlights at all times",
                "Wear dark clothing to stand out against the road",
                "Keep a safe distance from other vehicles",
                "Use signals and position yourself conspicuously"
            ],
            "answer": "Use signals and position yourself conspicuously"
        },
        {
            "id": "22",
            "question" : "What should you do if your motorcycle starts skidding?",
            "options": [
                "Brake hard to regain control",
                "Steer in the opposite direction of the skid",
                "Continue in the same direction of the skid",
                "Let go of the handlebars"
            ],
            "answer": "Steer in the opposite direction of the skid"
        },
        {
            "id": "23",
            "question" : "In Nepal, what is the legal speed limit for motorcycles on highways?",
            "options": [
                "40 km/h",
                "50 km/h",
                "60 km/h",
                "80 km/h"
            ],
            "answer": "80 km/h"
        },
        {
            "id": "24",
            "question" : "When approaching a blind intersection, what should you do?",
            "options": [
                "Accelerate to pass through quickly",
                "Honk your horn repeatedly",
                "Slow down and be prepared to stop",
                "Close your eyes and hope for the best"
            ],
            "answer": "Slow down and be prepared to stop"
        },
        {
            "id": "25",
            "question" : "What is the correct hand signal for indicating a right turn?",
            "options": [
                "Extend your left arm straight out",
                "Extend your right arm straight out",
                "Extend your left arm and point upwards",
                "Extend your left arm and point to the right"
            ],
            "answer": "Extend your left arm and point to the right"
        },
        {
            "id": "26",
            "question" : "What is the correct procedure for starting a parked motorcycle?",
            "options": [
                "Shift into first gear and release the clutch quickly",
                "Apply the brakes and accelerate at the same time",
                "Pull in the clutch, shift into neutral, and start the engine",
                "Hold the clutch, shift into fifth gear, and release the clutch slowly"
            ],
            "answer": "Pull in the clutch, shift into neutral, and start the engine"
        },
        {
            "id": "27",
            "question" : "What does it mean if your motorcycle's engine suddenly stalls while riding?",
            "options": [
                "Your motorcycle needs maintenance",
                "The brakes are failing",
                "You should shift to a higher gear",
                "You should downshift to a lower gear"
            ],
            "answer": "You should downshift to a lower gear"
        },
        {
            "id": "28",
            "question" : "When riding a motorcycle, where should you position yourself within a lane?",
            "options": [
                "Always in the center of the lane",
                "As close to the left edge of the lane as possible",
                "As close to the right edge of the lane as possible",
                "Depends on traffic conditions and road width"
            ],
            "answer": "Depends on traffic conditions and road width"
        },
        {
            "id": "29",
            "question" : "What should you do if you experience a wobble or instability while riding?",
            "options": [
                "Apply the brakes abruptly",
                "Grip the handlebars firmly and slow down gradually",
                "Accelerate to try to stabilize the motorcycle",
                "Take your feet off the foot pegs"
            ],
            "answer": "Grip the handlebars firmly and slow down gradually"
        },
        {
            "id": "30",
            "question" : "What should you do if you witness a collision or accident on the road?",
            "options": [
                "Ignore it and continue riding",
                "Stop and provide assistance if possible, and call for help",
                "Take pictures and post them on social media",
                "Blame the victims for not being careful"
            ],
            "answer": "Stop and provide assistance if possible, and call for help"
        },
        {
            "id": "31",
            "question" : "What should you do if you encounter strong crosswinds while riding?",
            "options": [
                "Lean into the wind to maintain balance",
                "Lean away from the wind to maintain balance",
                "Come to a complete stop and wait for the wind to subside",
                "Swerve left and right to counter the wind"
            ],
            "answer": "Lean into the wind to maintain balance"
        },
        {
            "id": "32",
            "question" : "What is the purpose of engine oil in a motorcycle?",
            "options": [
                "To cool down the engine",
                "To lubricate engine components and reduce friction",
                "To increase fuel efficiency",
                "To regulate exhaust emissions"
            ],
            "answer": "To lubricate engine components and reduce friction"
        },
        {
            "id": "33",
            "question" : "When riding in a group, what should you maintain to ensure safety?",
            "options": [
                "Ride as close as possible to the rider in front",
                "Maintain a staggered formation and proper spacing",
                "Ride in a single file to reduce confusion",
                "Ride in a parallel formation for better visibility"
            ],
            "answer": "Maintain a staggered formation and proper spacing"
        },
        {
            "id": "34",
            "question" : "What should you do if your motorcycle's throttle becomes stuck while riding?",
            "options": [
                "Panic and apply the brakes hard",
                "Shift to neutral and use the brakes to slow down",
                "Twist the throttle back and forth to release it",
                "Increase your speed to get to a safe area"
            ],
            "answer": "Shift to neutral and use the brakes to slow down"
        },
        {
            "id": "35",
            "question" : "What is the correct procedure for taking a turn on a motorcycle?",
            "options": [
                "Brake hard before the turn, then accelerate through the turn",
                "Accelerate through the turn",
                "Brake during the turn",
                "Slow down before the turn and accelerate gently through the turn"
            ],
            "answer": "Slow down before the turn and accelerate gently through the turn"
        },
        {
            "id": "36",
            "question" : "What is the primary purpose of wearing proper footwear while riding a motorcycle?",
            "options": [
                "To make a fashion statement",
                "To keep your feet cool",
                "To improve fuel efficiency",
                "To protect your feet and provide proper grip on the foot pegs"
            ],
            "answer": "To protect your feet and provide proper grip on the foot pegs"
        },
        {
            "id": "37",
            "question" : "What is the correct hand signal for indicating a left turn?",
            "options": [
                "Extend your left arm straight out",
                "Extend your right arm straight out",
                "Extend your left arm and point upwards",
                "Extend your left arm and point to the left"
            ],
            "answer": "Extend your left arm and point to the left"
        },
        {
            "id": "38",
            "question" : "What should you do if you see a vehicle with a 'Learner' sign on the road?",
            "options": [
                "Overtake it quickly",
                "Be patient and give them space",
                "Honk at them to hurry up",
                "Tailgate them to pressure them to go faster"
            ],
            "answer": "Be patient and give them space"
        },
        {
            "id": "39",
            "question" : "In Nepal, what is the minimum legal tread depth for motorcycle tires?",
            "options": [
                "1.0 mm",
                "1.5 mm",
                "2.0 mm",
                "2.5 mm"
            ],
            "answer": "1.0 mm"
        },
        {
            "id": "40",
            "question" : "What should you do if you experience a sudden puncture or blowout in a tire while riding?",
            "options": [
                "Brake hard to stop quickly",
                "Accelerate to maintain control",
                "Grip the handlebars firmly and gradually reduce speed",
                "Swerve to the side of the road"
            ],
            "answer": "Grip the handlebars firmly and gradually reduce speed"
        },
        {
            "id": "41",
            "question" : "When riding in heavy rain, what should you do to improve visibility?",
            "options": [
                "Turn off the headlights to reduce glare",
                "Ride in the center of the lane",
                "Use high beam headlights",
                "Use low beam headlights and increase following distance"
            ],
            "answer": "Use low beam headlights and increase following distance"
        },
        {
            "id": "42",
            "question" : "What should you do if you encounter gravel or loose debris on the road while riding?",
            "options": [
                "Accelerate to get through it quickly",
                "Brake hard to avoid skidding",
                "Maintain a steady speed and ride straight through",
                "Swerve and change lanes"
            ],
            "answer": "Maintain a steady speed and ride straight through"
        },
        {
            "id": "43",
            "question" : "What is the correct procedure for carrying a passenger on your motorcycle?",
            "options": [
                "Instruct them to hold onto your waist and lean with you",
                "Instruct them to hold onto the seat and lean in the opposite direction",
                "Instruct them to hold onto the handlebars",
                "Instruct them to hold onto the fuel tank"
            ],
            "answer": "Instruct them to hold onto your waist and lean with you"
        },
        {
            "id": "44",
            "question" : "In Nepal, what is the legal requirement for using a horn on a motorcycle?",
            "options": [
                "Horn should be used frequently to clear traffic",
                "Horn should not be used unnecessarily",
                "Horn should be used only during the night",
                "Horn should be used continuously while riding"
            ],
            "answer": "Horn should not be used unnecessarily"
        },
        {
            "id": "45",
            "question" : "What is the proper way to navigate a curve or turn on a motorcycle?",
            "options": [
                "Brake hard while turning",
                "Lean your body without leaning the motorcycle",
                "Lean the motorcycle and your body together in the direction of the turn",
                "Accelerate while turning"
            ],
            "answer": "Lean the motorcycle and your body together in the direction of the turn"
        },
        {
            "id": "46",
            "question" : "What should you do if you are about to collide with another vehicle?",
            "options": [
                "Brake hard to stop",
                "Swerve quickly to avoid the collision",
                "Stay in your lane and brace for impact",
                "Sound your horn repeatedly"
            ],
            "answer": "Brake hard to stop"
        },
        {
            "id": "47",
            "question" : "What is the primary cause of motorcycle accidents at intersections?",
            "options": [
                "Motorcycles being too fast",
                "Other vehicles failing to yield the right of way",
                "Poor road conditions",
                "Weather conditions"
            ],
            "answer": "Other vehicles failing to yield the right of way"
        },
        {
            "id": "48",
            "question" : "What is the correct lane position for avoiding oil patches or slippery surfaces?",
            "options": [
                "Ride in the left portion of the lane",
                "Ride in the center portion of the lane",
                "Ride in the right portion of the lane",
                "Constantly switch between lanes"
            ],
            "answer": "Ride in the center portion of the lane"
        },
        {
            "id": "49",
            "question" : "What should you do if you encounter an aggressive driver on the road?",
            "options": [
                "Engage in a race with them",
                "Make gestures and provoke them",
                "Ignore them and continue riding safely",
                "Tailgate and confront them"
            ],
            "answer": "Ignore them and continue riding safely"
        },
        {
            "id": "50",
            "question" : "In Nepal, what is the legal requirement for wearing a helmet while riding a motorcycle?",
            "options": [
                "Helmets are not mandatory",
                "Helmets are mandatory only for new riders",
                "Helmets are mandatory for all riders and passengers",
                "Helmets are mandatory only on highways"
            ],
            "answer": "Helmets are mandatory for all riders and passengers"
        },
        {
            "id": "51",
            "question" : "What is the primary cause of most motorcycle accidents?",
            "options": [
                "Brake failure",
                "Excessive speeding",
                "Poor road conditions",
                "Engine malfunction"
            ],
            "answer": "Excessive speeding"
        },
        {
            "id": "52",
            "question" : "When should you use your motorcycle's indicators or turn signals?",
            "options": [
                "Only during emergencies",
                "Whenever you feel like it",
                "Before changing lanes or turning",
                "Only when riding in a group"
            ],
            "answer": "Before changing lanes or turning"
        },
        {
            "id": "53",
            "question" : "In Nepal, what is the legal requirement for using rear-view mirrors on a motorcycle?",
            "options": [
                "Mirrors are optional",
                "At least one mirror is mandatory",
                "Mirrors are required only for high-speed riding",
                "Mirrors are required only for new motorcycles"
            ],
            "answer": "At least one mirror is mandatory"
        },
        {
            "id": "54",
            "question" : "What should you do if you are being tailgated by another vehicle?",
            "options": [
                "Speed up and try to lose them",
                "Increase your following distance",
                "Brake suddenly to warn them",
                "Wave at them to go around you"
            ],
            "answer": "Increase your following distance"
        },
        {
            "id": "55",
            "question" : "When should you use your motorcycle's high beam headlights?",
            "options": [
                "At all times for better visibility",
                "Only in urban areas",
                "Only during the day",
                "When riding in remote areas with no traffic"
            ],
            "answer": "When riding in remote areas with no traffic"
        },
        {
            "id": "56",
            "question" : "In Nepal, what is the legal age requirement for a pillion (passenger) on a motorcycle?",
            "options": [
                "No age restriction for pillion riders",
                "At least 12 years old",
                "At least 16 years old",
                "At least 18 years old"
            ],
            "answer": "At least 12 years old"
        },
        {
            "id": "57",
            "question" : "What should you do if you experience a 'tank slapper' or handlebar wobble?",
            "options": [
                "Accelerate to stabilize the motorcycle",
                "Brake hard to stop",
                "Grip the handlebars firmly and ease off the throttle",
                "Let go of the handlebars and brace for impact"
            ],
            "answer": "Grip the handlebars firmly and ease off the throttle"
        },
        {
            "id": "58",
            "question" : "What is the correct procedure for riding in strong crosswinds?",
            "options": [
                "Lean into the wind to maintain balance",
                "Lean away from the wind to maintain balance",
                "Maintain a straight upright position",
                "Stop and wait for the wind to subside"
            ],
            "answer": "Maintain a straight upright position"
        },
        {
            "id": "59",
            "question" : "When is it appropriate to share a lane with another vehicle?",
            "options": [
                "Always, for better visibility",
                "Only when traffic is moving slowly",
                "Never, it's unsafe",
                "Only when overtaking another vehicle"
            ],
            "answer": "Never, it's unsafe"
        },
        {
            "id": "60",
            "question" : "What should you do if you experience a sudden rain shower while riding?",
            "options": [
                "Ride at your normal speed and you'll get through it quickly",
                "Brake hard to reduce speed",
                "Pull over and wait for the rain to stop",
                "Reduce speed and increase following distance"
            ],
            "answer": "Reduce speed and increase following distance"
        }
    
]
